Next thing we want to talk about is we continue to talk about controlling the ball using your chest to do a chest trap.
What you want to do with the chest trap is as you see the ball coming in you want to get it into your chest and drop it to the ground, again so you can step and make a good pass.
So you watch the ball in, it traps, drops at your feet.
You don't want the ball to fly off, you don't want it to hit at your side and let fly that way or that way, you want to stay square to the ball as it comes in moving your feet so that you're square to the ball, getting a good trap, step and pass.
Let's watch this demonstration.
Ball goes up, traps it right to his feet so he has control of the ball.
Notice how he leans back, allows the ball to come to him and makes that pass.
He even passes it with his right and left foot.
Same thing here as you get better at it you can begin to valley the ball.
Trap and don't even let the ball hit the ground, valley it right back to the person.
Nice and in control and nice pass.